TV를 볼 때에는 방을 밝게 하고 TV에서 떨어져서 봅시다.
When you're watching television, be sure to keep your room bright and keep distance from the TV!
강하게... 곱게...
Strong and gentle...
우리는 SUPER GUYS
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
메다로트: 혼
Medarot: Spirits
(Medarotto Damashī)
무적의 히로야!!
We are matchless heroes!!
태어난 그 순간이
The very moment of being born
기적을 부르는 사랑과 정의
It is the love and justice calling for a miracle
멀리 떨어져 있어도
Even when separated by distance
믿는 불꽃의 혼
The spirit of flame believes in each other
흘러라 빛나는 땀!
Flow! Sparkling sweat!
불타는 혼
Burning spirit!
둘이서라면 무한의 파워!
When there are two, infinite power shows itself!
꿈이여 펼쳐져라!
Let dreams unfold!
우리는 SUPER GUYS!
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
고고한 히로야!!
We are lonely yet proud heroes!!
볼링했더니 벌써 시간이 이렇게!
I only bowled for a while, and it's already late!
이렇게는 또 엄마한테 혼나겠어!
My mom will scold me again!
누구냐!
Who's there!?
너는...!
You...!
수수께끼의 메다로터!
The Mysterious Medarotter!
뭐, 뭔 일이냐!
W- what's your business!?
데스 메다로트를 파괴하러 왔다.
I'm here to destroy your Death Medarot.
뭐, 뭐라고!?
W- what!?
흥! 이 내게 로보틀을 걸어 오다니 대단하군!
Hmph! You want a Robattle against me? Bring it on!
해치워 버려, 키리킨자무!
Take them down, Kiri Kinzam!
끝내라, 도쿠스.
Finish it, Dorcus.
예, 마스터.
Yes, Master.
져, 졌다...
I... I lost...
수수께끼의 도쿠스 사용자라? 역시 넌 나하고 닮았어.
Mysterious Dorcus Wielder, eh? You sure are like me.
돌아가자, 우라가스미.
Let's go back, Uragasumi.
알겠습니다, 도련님.
Understood, young master.
전사의 정: 전편
Compassion of Warriors: Part 1
(en: Dark Alliance: Part I)
멈춰, 메타비! 왜 도망치는 거야!
Stop, Metabee! Why are you running away!?
오늘은 1년에 1번 있는 배터리 충전일이야!
Today's that day of the year - battery recharging day!
야, 그러니까 왜 그런 날에 다같이 해수욕하러 가는 거야!?
Hey, let me ask you this first; why are you going to beach in a day like this!?
어쩔 수 없잖아! 오늘 안 가면 여름이 끝나!
Is there anything that we can do, then? Today is the last day of summer!
-안녕하세요!
-실례합니다.
-Good morning!
-We're here!
여름이 끝나면 못 가냐!
Nothing stops us from going to beach after summer!
뭐야, 뭐야! 아리카하고 유즈루도 같이 가는 거야!?
What is this!? Are Arika and Yuzuru joining you!?
다같이 날 따돌리는 거야!?
Are you leaving me out all together!?
나중에 봐~ 집 잘 보고 있어!
See ya! Take care of the house!
싫어싫어! 나도 해수욕하러 가고 싶어!
No way, never! I wanna join you to beach, too!
제멋대로 굴지 마! 배터리 충전하지 않으면 후회할 거야!
Don't be stupid! Recharge your battery, or you're gonna regret it!
해수욕! 해수욕! 해수욕!
Beach! Beach! Beach!
배터리 충전을 내일로 미루어서 잘 됐어.
So, you're recharging in tomorrow instead of today? Good for you!
도중에 꺼져도 몰라.
Even if your power goes down, it's your problem.
흥! 오늘 하루 정도는 정신력으로 버틸 수 있어!
Hmph! My willpower is enough to stand for a day!
정신력으로 버틴다니?
Willpower instead of battery, eh?
-메타비가
-충전하지 않고
-해수욕.
-Metabee
-went to beach
-without recharging?
이거 재밌구나! 바로 코쿠류 씨한테 보고다!
Isn't it interesting!? We're going to report to Mr. Kokuryu right away!
가자!
Let's go!
아, 두목!
Hey, boss!
분명 해수욕에 초대받지 못해서 실눈을 뜨고 보고 있던 거야!
She must have been mad at them for not inviting her to beach!
그러게.
Yeah...
KLN형 유니트리스
KLN Type Unitrix
가라! 유니트리스!
Go, Unitrix!
레클리스 모드!
Reckless Mode!
숨어도 소용없어!
No use hiding!
서모그래피 온!
Thermography On!
어때? 신형 데스 메다로트 감촉.
How's the new Death Medarot working for you?
최고야!
It's the best!
이거 정말 가져도 돼?
Can I really have this?
그래, 맘대로 써.
Yeah, use it as much as you want.
좋았어! 그럼 두말없이 가져갈게!
Great! Then I'll be taking this without any hesitation!
이 유니트리스라면 절대 지지 않을 수 있을 거야!
With this Unitrix, I cannot lose!
기다려라, 수수께끼의 메다로터 씨야!
Just you wait, you Mr. Mysterious Medarotter!
저, 저기...
E- excuse me...
왜 왔냐!
Why are you here!?
아니, 실은 여러분께 솔깃한 정보가!
Well, that's, I got an interesting information for you two!
뭐야? 말해 봐!
What is it? Spit it out!
머신건 파츠!
Machine Gun Part!
뭐라고!?
What did you say!?
뭐, 됐어.
Good enough.
말해 봐.
Tell me.
실은 잇키 놈, 메타비 배터리 충전하지 않고 해수욕하러 갔어여!
Listen closely! Ikki went to beach, but he didn't recharge Metabee!
배터리 충전 안 하고?
Metabee's not recharged?
배터리 잔량이 적으면 제대로 못 움직여여!
When his battery level is low, he can't move properly!
메타비를 쳐부술 최고의 기회에여!
It's the perfect chance to destroy Metabee!
최고의 기회? 지금 난 그런 건 상관 없어!
Perfect chance? I don't need things like that anymore!
어?
Huh?
이 유니트리스가 있으면, 설사 수영장 안에서라고 해도 메타비 따위는 한방에 쓰러트릴 수 있어!
With this Unitrix, even in pools, I can take Metabee down with one hit!
오오옹!
Ooooooohhhhhhh
뭐, 그래도 유니트리스 성능 시험하기에는 마침 잘 됐네! 좋아! 지금 바로 안내해!
Well, but still, you're here just in time. I had to test Unitrix's performance anyway. Alright! Lead me to them!
네! 맡겨 주세요!
Got it! Leave it to us!
어이! 봐 봐!
Hey! Look at me!
어?
Huh?
메타비 씨 멋져!
Mr. Metabee, you look cool!
꼴불견이네. 너도 메타비같이 멋진 척이라도 해 봐라.
How unsightly. Try acting cool like Metabee at least!
젠장! 너무 까불면 배터리 없어진다!
Damn! Stop fooling around or your battery depletes!
괜찮다니까?
I'm fine, I'm fine!
구려!
How unsightly!
왜 웃고 있지? 배터리가 없어서 언제 멈출 지 모르는데.
Why is he laughing? He might stop functioning by battery depletion anytime.
이번에야말로 정신력, 정신력이다!
I will do this! I got willpower! Willpower!
설마 정말 정신력으로 어떻게 될 거라고 믿고 있는 건가?
Is he actually believing in his willpower?
메타비, 이제 그만두라니까!
Metabee, you should give up!
이러고 있으니 왠지 옛날이 생각나.
It's just like how we were back in the past.
아야야야야야야!
Ouchchchchch!
엄마!
Mom!
목말라!
I'm thirsty!
주스 마시고 싶어!
I wanna get some juice!
그럼 이걸로 모두 먹을 만큼 사 와.
Then go buy enough juice for everyone.
나 복숭아맛!
I'd like to get a peach!
그럼 나는 보리차.
I'm for barley tea.
복숭아맛하고 보리차지?
Peach juice and barley tea?
가자, 메타비!
Let's go, Metabee!
그래!
Right!
아, 탄산 안 들어있는 걸로 사 와!
Hey, be sure that mine is not a soda!
뭔 일이에요?
What's wrong?
아니, 보아하니 자고 일어났더니 해파리한테 물린 것 같아.
It seems that a jellyfish bit me while I was sleeping.
여기서 해파리에게!?
Jellyfish? Up here!?
어?
What?
저런저런.
My, my.
보리차하고 복숭아!
Barley tea and peach!
여, 잇키! 이런 곳에서 만나다니 인연이네!
Hey, Ikki! What a coincidence!
뭐야, 키쿠히메하고 니들도 왔냐?
Oh, Kikuhime and you guys!
야, 주스가 공짜래서 왔어!
Hey, I heard that juice is free around here!
뭐!?
What!?
저기 판매대에서 행사하고 있대!
That stand over there is doing an event!
어서 가지 않으면 없어질걸?
Hurry up, or nothing will be left!
가 보자, 메타비!
Let's go, Metabee!
공짜로 얻은 주스를 산 걸로 하면 받은 돈은 전부 내 용돈이 되는 거야!
If I take the free juice and tell them I bought those, then all the money will be my extra allowance!
너 교활한 거에는 머리 참 잘도 돌아간다.
Aren't you clever when it comes to stinginess?
그래도 이런 곳에서 주스를 판다고?
But still, a juice stand, up here?
주스라면 내가 한 턱 쏠게.
Let me buy you some juice.
어?
Huh?
나하고 로보틀해서 이긴다면 말야!
If you win in a Robattle against me, that is!
잘 꼬았네요, 두목!
You lured them well, boss!
너희들 속였구나!
You guys fooled me!
흥! 유니트리스 전송!
Hmph! Transfer Unitrix!
도망은 못 치지.
You can't run away.
언제나 그랬듯이 억지부리냐, 긴카이!
You're forcible as always, Ginkai!
자, 나하고 싸워라!
Now, fight me!
그런 소리를 들어도 말이지...
He said that, but...
이렇게 되면 할 수밖에 없어!
Now that it came to this, we have to do it!
바보야! 너 배터리 아주 조금밖에 안 남았어!
You idiot! Your battery level is dangerously low!
지금 로보틀하기는 완전 무리야!
You can't possibly think about doing Robattles now!
맡겨 둬! 1분이면 끝나.
Leave it to me! One minute is enough to finish this.
그래, 그럼 해 보자!
If you say so! Let's do this!
늦네, 잇키하고 메타비.
Ikki and Metabee are late...
어디까지 사러 간 거야?
How far did they go to buy those?
어디에 들렀다 오는 거 아니야?
Aren't they taking their time?
잠깐 저 찾으러 갔다 올게요.
I'll go find them.
젠장!
Damn!
가라, 유니트릭스!
Go, Unitrix!
메타비!
Metabee!
점점 배터리 잔량이 줄어들고 있어!
Battery level is getting lower and lower!
몸이... 무거워...
My body... feels heavy...
역시 로보틀은 배터리 소비가 심해!
Robattles sure deplete a lot of battery!
메타비!
Metabee!
이제 관둬! 이 이상은 무리야!
Stop it! You can't do this anymore!
흥, 이래선 상대가 안 되는데.
Hmph. What a weak opponent.
제기랄!
Damn!
메타비!
Metabee!
이걸로 끝이다!
You're going down!
메타비! 달아나!
Metabee! Run!
잇키. 이제 손가락 하나... 못 까딱...
Ikki. I can't move... my finger...
그만해! 이제 승부 났잖아!
Stop it! The match is set!
메타비!
Metabee!
흥. 사정 거리를 벗어났군.
Hmph. They're out of reach.
젠장! 저런 놈, 배터리만 남아 있었다면!
Dammit! If only he had more battery!
가자, 유니트리스.
Let's go back, Unitrix.
잠깐.
Stop.
도쿠스 전송.
Transfer Dorcus.
저건...
That guy...
수수께끼의 메다로터!
The Mysterious Medarotter!
내가 상대하지.
Let me face you.
나타났구나.
So he's here.
너하고 만나길 바라고 있었어!
I was waiting for you to show up!
어젯밤의 원한은 받은 만큼 되갚아줄 테니까!
I'll pay you back as much as you did to me yesterday night!
저딴 놈 해치워버려!
Take him down!
내게 손가락질하지 마라.
Don't point at me.
나는 데스 메다로트를 쓰러뜨리고 싶을 뿐.
I simply want to take Death Medarots down.
너희 동료인 게 아니다.
I am not your friend.
조잘조잘 시끄럽게! 가라, 유니트리스!
You're annoying! Go, Unitrix!
여기다.
Here.
레클리스 모드!
Reckless Mode!
뭐야!?
What!?
레클리스 모드로 변형했어? 레클리스 모드!
He transformed into Reckless Mode too? Reckless Mode!
흥. 그렇게 되지 않으면 재미없지!
Hmph! Now this is getting interesting!
뭐야뭐야? 다들 레클리스 모드로 변형할 수 있는 거야?
What is this? Can everyone transform into Reckless Mode now?
숨어, 도쿠스.
Hide, Dorcus.
지가 교활한 줄 알고 있어.
You think you're cunning, eh?
서모그래피 온!
Thermography On!
지금이야, 도쿠스!
Now, Dorcus!
잡았다!
You're mine!
기능 정지. 기능 정지.
Function ceased. Function ceased.
다 보이거든?
I can see everything!
도쿠스가 졌어.
Dorcus has lost.
알겠냐!
Do you see now!?
이제 내 앞에서 잘난 척 마라!
Don't try to act big in front of me anymore!
도쿠스.
Dorcus.
수수께끼의 메다로터도 못 이긴다니...
That Mysterious Medarotter couldn't win too...
젠장! 데스 메다로터에게 지다니!
Damn! How could I lose to a Death Medarotter!?
젠장! 제기랄! 망할!
Damn! Dammit! Damn!
데스 메다로터에게 진 게 그렇게 분해?
Is being lost to a Death Medarotter that mortifying?
넌...
You...
잠깐 네게 할 말이 있어.
I have something to say to you.
정말, 배터리가 거의 없는 상태에서 로보틀을 하다니, 뭔 생각이야?
Robattling when battery isn't enough? What were you thinking!?
그러니까, 어쩔 수 없었어! 상대가 갑자기 덤벼들었어!
Again, it couldn't be helped! The opponent suddenly showed up!
그래도 수수께끼의 메다로터도 못 이기다니...
But still, that Mysterious Medarotter couldn't win...
그래도 메타비가 완전히 충전만 되면 그딴 놈!
But when Metabee has his battery fully charged, he's nothing!
안돼.
No.
잇키 씨, 행복해 보여.
Mr. Ikki, you look happy.
이 이상 데스 메다로트는 없는 척 하고 사는 게 좋아. 상대하면 안돼.
You'd better forget about Death Medarots from now on. Don't fight them anymore.
으, 으응.
R- right.
귀여워 보여.
Cute...
뭐, 뭐야, 너희들.
W- what's wrong with you guys?
한번 말해주지 않을래?
Wouldn't you like to tell me?
뭘?
Tell you what?
너는 왜 그렇게 데스 메다로트를 싫어하는 거야?
Why do you hate Death Medarots that much?
너하고는 상관 없어.
It has nothing to do with you.
뭐, 됐어.
Well, good enough.
어쨌든 오늘 로보틀로 깨달았지?
Anyway, I hope you realized that by today's Robattle.
메다로트 사의 제품으로는 데스 메다로트는 못 이긴다는 걸.
You cannot defeat Death Medarot with the products of Medarot Company.
네게 보여주고 싶은 게 있어. 따라 와.
I have something that I want to show you. Follow me.
STG형 엑스사이즈
STG Type Excise
이건...
This...
신형 데스 메다로트, 엑스사이즈의 프로토타입이야.
This is the prototype of a new Death Medarot, Excise.
엑스사이즈.
Excise.
자, 쇼를 시작할게.
Let the show begin.
엑스사이즈, 고!
Excise, go!
뭐, 뭐야, 이 수치는?
W- what's up with these values?
전투력. 기동력. 방어력.
Offensive power. Mobility power. Defensive power.
전부 월등하잖아!
Everything is so exceptional!
데스 메다로트의 개발이 여기까지 진행됐다니.
The development of Death Medarots is already on this level?
네 도쿠스를 쓰러트린 유니트리스도 이거하고 같은 성능을 가지고 있어.
Unitrix, which took down your Dorcus, has the same performance with this one.
데스 메다로트를 쓰러트리려면 데스 메다로트가 아니면 불가능해.
Only Death Medarot can take down a Death Medarot.
괜찮으면 이 엑스사이즈, 네게 줄게.
If you'd like, you can have this Excise.
뭐라고!?
What!?
왜 나한테?
Why would you give that to me?
네 전투 방식이 마음에 들었어.
I like your way of fighting.
알고 있긴 해?
Do you even know?
내 목적은 데스 메다로트를 쓰러트리는 거야.
My objective is to take down all the Death Medarots.
그래, 알아. 몇이고 쓰러트려 줘.
Yes, I know. Take them down as much as possible.
데스 메다로트로 로보틀에서 질 놈에게 데스 메다로터가 될 자격은 없으니까.
If someone loses a Robattle using Death Medarot, that guy do not deserve to be a Death Medarotter.
다만.
But.
엑스사이즈를 네게 주는 거에는 조건이 둘 있어.
I'll need you to abide by 2 conditions if you want Excise.
조건?
Conditions?
그래. 첫째는 지금 파트너인 도쿠스를 버리는 거.
Yes. First is to abandon your current partner, Dorcus.
도쿠스를 버려?
Abandon Dorcus?
그리고 또 하나의 조건은...
And the another condition is...
그리 되었으니 너하고는 오늘까지다.
And that's why we're parting as of today.
저는 마스터의 지시를 따를 뿐입니다.
I follow Master's orders, and that's all.
그럼.
See you.
예, 마스터.
Understood, Master.
유니트리스한테 이기기 위해서는 그 재빠른 반사 신경을 어떻게 해야...
I have to do something with that swift reflexes to defeat Unitrix...
예를 들어 레클리스 모드로 단숨에 곁으로 뛰어든다던가.
Like, pouncing into him in one breath using Reckless Mode.
안 되지. 유니트리스도 레클리스 모드로 변형 가능하잖아! 진짜!
It won't work... Unitrix can transform into Reckless Mode too! Ugh!
잠깐. 너 소리 내고 있어!
Hey. You're thinking by speaking out loud!
수업중이야.
Class is in session.
죄송합니다.
I'm sorry.
두목! 준비 OK에요!
Boss! We're ready!
좋아! 코쿠류 씨한테 받은 새 파트, 바로 시험해 보자!
Alright! Let us test out the new parts from Mr. Kokuryu right now!
페퍼캣!
Peppercat!
쏴!
Fire!
있다!
There!
으아! 오지 마, 오지 마!
Wah! Don't come!
위험해!
This is bad!
어떻게 해도 안 멈추어져!
I can't stop this!
야! 긴카이 놈들 아지트 어디냐!
Hey! Where is Ginkai and others' hideout?!
긴카이 아지트는...
Ginkai's hideout is...
도부로크 신도시의 아무도 안 쓰는 볼링장이야!
...the abandoned bowling center in Doburoku New Town!
아무도 안 쓰는 볼링장이군!
Abandoned bowling center, it is!
잠깐! 잇키! 좀 도와줘!
Wait, Ikki! Help me!
여기야.
Here we are.
이 이상 데스 메다로트는 없는 척 하고 사는 게 좋아. 상대하면 안돼.
You'd better forget about Death Medarots from now on. Don't fight them anymore.
미안, 나에 씨. 그래도 역시 그냥은 못 넘어가겠어.
Sorry, Ms. Nae. But I can't let this pass.
나도... 메타비도...
I... or Metabee...
역시 블랙!
Black coffees are the best!
야!
Hey!
오늘은 그때처럼은 안 될 거다!
You aren't gonna win today!
너도 참 질리지도 않는 놈이구나? 좋아.
Aren't you stubborn? Well then.
상대해 주지!
Let me face you!
잠깐.
Stop.
마침 잘 됐어. 너희들에게 꼭 알맞은 상대가 왔어.
You're just in time. I have a perfect opponent for you guys.
수, 수수께끼의 메다로터.
T- the Mysterious Medarotter.
얘가 동료라고?
He's our friend now?
엑스사이즈를 손에 넣기 위한 또 하나의 조건은
The other condition of having Excise is...
네 손으로 메타비를 쓰러트리는 거야.
...taking Metabee down with your own hands.
잇키. 내가 상대다.
Ikki. You're fighting me.
뭐라고?!
What did you say?!
네가 데스 메다로트를 손에 넣으면 무적이 될 거야. 데스 메다로터는 지면 안 돼.
When you have Death Medarot in your control, you're invincible. A Death Medarotter never loses.
너같은 사람이야말로 참된 데스 메다로터의 이름이 어울려.
You are suited to have the name of the true Death Medarotter.
자, 보여 줘. 참된 데스 메다로터의 전투를.
Now, show me the battle of the true Death Medarotter.
아침은 싫어하지만 어느 날 돌연
Mornings are not my favorite, but someday on a sudden
자명종 울리기 전에 일어났어
I woke up before my alarm clock rings
내 가슴이 메어지게 괴로워
My wringing heart is so troubled
슬픈 만큼 당신은 연상의 사람
As much as I'm sad, you are older than me
쭉 보고 있어도 닿지 않아
Gazing at you isn't getting me through
키하고 하트
Height and heart
빛나는 미소는
Is the shining smile
우러러 볼 뿐만인 태양?
nothing more than a sun that I admire?
Don't mind 신경쓰지 마
Don't mind, don't make it let you down
My girl 쏘아올리기 전에
To my girl, before you make a dash,
Fight mind 무기력함에 져 버린다면
have a fighting mindset! If you lose to timorousness,
사랑은 잡을 수 없어
you cannot catch the love
차회예고
Preview for Next Episode
도쿠스를 버리고 데스 메다로터가 된 수수께끼의 메다로터.
Having abandoned Dorcus, the Mysterious Medarotter became a Death Medarotter.
규칙도 자존심도 버린 고독한 로보틀이 계속된다.
Lonesome Robattles continue, without rules or pride.
어느새 그의 메다로트 혼이 끊어진 것인가.
Did his Medarot spirit vanish at last?
그를 구하기 위해 잇키가, 메타비가, 그리고 도쿠스가 일어선다.
To save him, Ikki, Metabee, and Dorcus stand up.
메다로트 혼의 다음 이야기! 전사의 정: 후편
Next time on Medarot Damashii! Compassion of Warriors: Part 2
타올라라, 뜨거운 혼이여!
Let the hot spirit burn up!